

tl;dr

Software engineer with 6 years of experience, fascination for intriguing computer science problems and a flair for Systems programming & anything DevOps. Believes in using the right tool for the right job. Finds home coding in Golang and talking about Python or Clojure(depends on the company).

Experience _

SIGHUP Srl Milan, Italy

KUBERNETES ENGINEER May 2021 - Present

I own the maintanence of a CNCF certified Open Source Kubernetes Distro called Fury. Keeping the component applications up-to-date and working on latest k8s runtimes, adding new tools to the landspace, writing k8s controllers for health check in the cluster, etc.

Quick Algorithm Srl Milan, Italy

TECH LEAD April 2018 - April 2021

I help develop the scalable infrastructure for the data crunching algorithms that the company offer as a service. My job involved deploying and managing the infrastructure which includes our own data vizualization platform and several pipelines for. I also managed the engineering team of strength 5.

Pears Remote

CORE DEVELOPER July 2016 - Present

Pears is a free and open source, distributed, and lightweight search engine using distributional semantics technique. The project has been funded so far by the University of Cambridge and the Mozilla foundation. Develops critical components of the product.

Red Hat Inc.

Bangalore, India

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER (PYTHON, C)

January 2015 - June 2016

Worked as a member of the Gluster filesystem development team. Wrote features and tools both in C and Python to improve the performance and usability of the product.

Bang The Table Pvt. Ltd.

Bangalore, India

RUBY ON RAILS SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

May 2014 - Dec. 2014

Implemented many enhancement features like survey, pools, etc. to the community engagement platform EngagementHQ for Australian, New Zealand, and Canadian Govt. Worked with the customer support team to fix core product issues by meeting SLAs

Other Achievements & Awards

- University of Cambridge sponsorship The PeARS team was invited over to the University of Cambridge to be a part of the workshop series on Open source and NLP and to meet and work w
- 2016 Cambridge to be a part of the workshop series on Open source and NLP and to meet and work with the team face-to-face.
- 2014 **Google Women Techmaker India** Was one among the 10 winners of Women Techmaker award given away by Google
- 2013 **Linux foundation training scholarship** Won the Linux Foundation Training Scholarship awarded only to 5 people around the world under the category System Administration WhizKid
- 2013 **Red Hat scholarship** Won a scholarship from Red Hat, where I was completely sponsored to attend the RHCSA training
- **Google Summer of Code** Successfully implemented a framework in Python to automatically test the fonts rendered by engines as the Google Summer of Code project under the organization
- Swathanthra Malayalam Computing in the domain Natural Language Processing

Trainings & Certifications _____

2021	Certified Kubernetes Application Developer - Passed the CKAD certification by CNCF in July 2021. This exam certifies that candidates can design, build and deploy cloud-native applications for Kubernetes.	Remote
2017	Recurse Center - Got selected for a 3 month programmers' retreat in which computer science enthusiasts from all around the world participated and exchanged knowdledge	New York City
2013	Linux Foundation System Administration certification - Completed the Linux Foundation sys admin course	Remote
2013	Red Hat Certified System Administration course(RHCSA) - Completed RHCSA training covering advanced topics in system administration	Bangalore, India

Education _____

Politecnico Di Milano Milano, Italy

MASTER OF SCIENCE (LAUREA MAGISTRALE) IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

September 2017 - 2020

NSS College of Engineering (affiliated to the University of Calicut)

Palakkad, India Mar. 2010 - April 2014

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Technical Skills _____

Tools - Kubernetes, Terraform, ArgoCD, Tekton, Ansible, Gitlab CI/CD, Tilt, etc.

Programming Languages - Golang, Python, Clojure, C, Ruby, Elixir

Cloud Providers - AWS, GCP, Azure, vSphere

Operating Systems - GNU/Linux (Fedora, Debian and its derivatives, Arch Linux, & similar Linus distros)